Thank you.
Hello, Clark.
My name is Kara.
I'm from Krypton.
Thank you.
I made this whole world shine for you
Yeah, yeah, come on
Kara, I don't know where you heard about Krypton,
but an astronomer told me that planet was destroyed.
Its physical form is gone, but it still lives on through us.
Here, this will warm you up.
It's hot tea.
Young lady, I'm sure that your parents are very worried about you.
Why don't you let us call them?
There's no one to call.
Well, you can't sleep out in the field.
You'll stay with us tonight.
Thank you.
I heard you were very kind.
How exactly did you get here?
I came here to see you.
I came through a passage in the cave wall.
A passage from where?
A place where all your questions will be answered.
Where you don't have to hide your true self.
Look, if you really are from some distant planet,
why don't you do us a favor, huh?
Give us a display of all of your special abilities.
Dad.
Clark.
You told me yourself that Pete's being harassed by the FBI.
How do we know that this isn't just some sort of a ploy?
Jonathan Kent.
You have no place in this conversation.
I will show Kal-El all he needs to see in due time.
Where did you hear that name?
It was given to you at birth.
Why are you here?
To take you home.
Clark?
Lex.
Hey, do you have a second?
This is, um...
Good time, isn't he?
I thought you'd be out celebrating.
Your dad's finally behind bars.
My father has a battalion of lawyers more powerful than Caesar's army.
He'll be out on bail unless for 48 hours.
I don't think the judge is gonna let a murderer back out on the street.
Clark, the only way he'll be denied bail
is if there's evidence at his bail hearing that he's an imminent threat to society.
What about Chloe's voicemail?
The one with your dad's confession on it?
That can be pretty damaging.
It will be, for the grand jury.
But in order to deny him bail, they need eyewitnesses.
People have seen my father actually inflict harm.
Unfortunately, anyone who's been in the same situation as me has.
Unfortunately, anyone who's been privy to his darkest moments
is either dead or unwilling to come forward.
I'll come forward.
I appreciate the support, Clark, but they need an eyewitness.
I saw him at Belle Reve.
I saw him order the doctor to increase your electroshock voltage.
Even when the doctor said it could turn you into a vegetable.
How could you have seen that?
I snuck in to try to save you, but I was too late.
You knew all along my father murdered his parents, didn't you?
And you never told me, Lex.
I always assumed there was a tacit agreement among friends
to share that kind of information with each other.
Not when it can get your friend killed.
Lex, your father threw you in a mental institution and fried your brain.
I don't know.
I don't know what happened.
If you found that out all over again, I thought he might kill you,
and I couldn't live with that.
You're a good friend, Clark.
If you tell the judge what you just told me,
my father will be exchanging his Armani for an orange jumpsuit.
I'll be there. You can count on it.
It was my fault.
Six-one, clear.
Coming up.
I thought we had a deal, loader.
Look, I tipped you off on your son's wire.
I made sure any discriminating recordings disappeared into the ether.
I can't control some bleached blonde, Polish or wannabe
from dredging up evidence for a decades-old homicide.
And our other investigation, Lex's friend, what's the status of that?
You're a piece of work.
In case you haven't noticed,
you're a hop, skip, and a jump away from death row.
And no hick farm kid's secret's gonna be able to save your ass.
This is just an inconvenience.
I'll be out on bail in a couple of hours.
And I expect you to send me the information
you've gathered so far on Clark Kent.
You can expect to be waiting for a very long time.
Our deal's over, Mr. Luther.
You're venturing into dangerous waters, Loader.
I'm a pretty decent swimmer.
Night-night.
Opening six-one.
You shouldn't involve yourself in their problems.
Lex is my friend. I want to help him.
You can't trust him.
You don't know him.
I don't have to.
It's human nature. It's just who they are.
They happen to be the people that I care about.
Which is why it'll be that much harder for you
when they all betray you.
I can understand why you're scared.
This is all you know.
But you're not meant for this world, Callow.
You were meant for mine.
My name's Clark.
And why should I believe anything you say?
Because it's the truth.
Really?
Why don't you start by telling me
where you've been for the last 14 years?
If you join me,
all your questions will be answered.
That's not good enough.
Callow, wait.
Come with me.
Why do you do this?
Tell me.
I can't help it.
Your will.
This is why you can't fly.
This is why you get to die.
Come!
juegos
?
Questo è comello
comello
How are you doing this?
You're doing it too.
I can't fly.
Miss Fissure wasn't here last week.
It opened to release me.
It'll open again when we go.
What makes you think I don't like this world?
I can sense how sad you are, Kal-El.
Not a day goes by where you don't feel like an outsider.
Even those closest to you will never truly understand you.
But it doesn't have to be that way.
It's not.
You've been down here ever since the meteor shower?
Yes.
Waiting for the time when he knew you'd be ready.
He?
Your birth father.
Jor-El.
He died in Krypton.
Yes, but...
his spirit and will live on inside these walls.
You should have known.
He's not the monster that you imagine.
He saved your life.
To turn me into something I never wanted to be.
You may think you know your destiny,
but you have no idea what greatness lies ahead of you.
Then why don't you tell me?
I'm only here to help your transition.
Everything that you want to know lies through there.
I'm here to help you.
But it has to be your choice.
Come with me, Kal-El.
I can't do this.
Just know...
when you're ready,
I'll be waiting for you.
Orange is a good color for you, Dad.
Although it might get a little old after 25 to life.
I didn't ask you here to trade insults.
No matter how wide the chasm gets between us, son,
I'm your father. I'll always be your father.
I'm the devil that's haunted me since the day I was born.
Lex, this is not easy for me.
I...
As a father, I, um...
I have failed you.
I realize that now.
And, uh...
I'm sorry.
Two years ago, I was diagnosed with a, um...
a degenerative liver disease.
I've tried everything. Everything imaginable.
But, um...
There's nothing.
It's too late.
No amount of money can save me.
Lex.
Please.
Don't let me die in prison.
Don't.
Dad
This might have been more effective
If you had a string quartet in the corner
Playing Barber's Requiem
I understand
How could you trust me?
I've asked my doctors to
Release my medical files to you
You can see for yourself
She hasn't eaten anything since she's been here
Martha, right now her appetite is the least of our problems
I think she's for real
I think Jor-El sent her
Are you sure?
How else can we explain her powers?
Clark, this is Smallville
Kryptonite's given a lot of people special abilities
She knows my birth name
She knows everything about me
She doesn't know anything more about you than Dr. Swan
Dr. Swan?
Do you think Swan sent Kara?
I have no idea what that man's agenda is
But wherever this girl is from
I just don't trust her
You're the one who cannot be trusted, Jonathan Kent
You broke the covenant
Jor-El gave you many warnings
But you chose not to listen to them
What is she talking about, Jonathan?
Tell Kal-El what you did
What kind of deal did you make, Dad?
I promised Jor-El that if he gave me the power to bring you back from Metropolis
That one day I would return you to him
Jonathan, you didn't do that
Martha, I had no idea it was going to be this soon
No
I told you, Kal-El
They'll always betray you
Even the man you call your father
I did not betray my son
Quiet
Someone's listening
What are you talking about?
How'd you do that?
Who are you?
Get out of my way!
What did you do to him?
That man feared you, Kal-El
He wanted to exploit you
So you killed him?
He didn't feel any pain
She killed a man, Jonathan
We have to call the sheriff
What are we going to do?
We're going to tell the sheriff
Sweetheart, that a Kryptonian girl vaporized a federal agent
What have you invited into our lives?
Martha, I honestly don't believe I had another choice
How could you have made a decision like that about our son without talking to me?
It was the only way that I could get him back
Why would you keep it a secret?
Because I didn't want you to have to wait for the rest of your life
Worrying about something that might not ever come to pass
Do you really think, Jonathan?
Do you really think Jor-El will ever give up on Clark?
I can't just sit idly by while he tries to take away our son
Well, we might not have a choice
That girl is more powerful than Clark
Mr. Kent
So this is the legendary torch
Yeah
A little less glamorous than you imagined, huh?
If you're looking for a new one, you're going to have to go to the store
I'm looking for Clark
I haven't seen a trace of him
I was looking for you
Something's telling me you're not here to throw a tea party
Look, I understand that you're very good at getting to the bottom of things
Do you think you could run the fingerprints off of this for me?
No problem
Um, is there a name that's attached to the fingerprints?
That's actually what I need you to find out for me, Chloe
I need the identity of the last person that touched that cup
Okay
Well, if I could get a little more info about the plot in this mystery, it might help us out
Chloe, as a personal favor to me, please don't press the issue
Okay, yeah
I'll call my guy right now
Thank you
It's going to take a little while
Of course
I thought you'd be packing
Well, if I squeezed anything else into my suitcases, I think they'd explode
So when are you taking off?
Well, I have to be at the airport by noon tomorrow
That's sort of why I'm here
I'm just wondering if you would mind being my supervisor
Sure
I know it's been a strange year, but I hate leaving with the feeling that things aren't settled between us
Lana, when I said I wanted you to be happy, I meant that
When you invited me over the other night, and you had something important to tell me, that wasn't it, was it?
Clark, if you have something to say to me, say it before I'm gone
Lana?
Who's that?
My cousin
You've never mentioned her before
Where's she from?
Far away
California
Well, you know, if you've...
If you've...
If you've got company, I should find a ride from someone else.
Lana, even though it's going to be hard to see you go, I want to be there for you.
Talk in the car tomorrow?
She really does love you.
But it's not meant to be, and you know that.
No one knows what's meant to be.
Not you, not even Jor-El.
Don't let it upset you, Kal-El.
What you share with Lana is an earthly love.
Filled with doubts and pain and sorrow.
The love between us will be stronger than anything.
Anything you can imagine.
You and I are the only ones left, Kal-El.
We're the only ones who can preserve the Kryptonian race.
Come with me, Kal-El.
Come home.
This is my home.
I know it seems that way.
But sooner or later, everyone you know here will lie, betray, or leave you.
No matter what you say, I'll never go with you.
Clarkette?
I have a package for you.
Thank you.
Where's it from?
A Mr. Lionel Luther.
Johns Hopkins?
Mayo Clinic?
My father's knocked on the door of every major medical institution in the Western world
and was sent home each time without a cure.
I'm sensing you're having second thoughts.
Lex, I understand if you want to back out.
I mean, he needs to be punished for what he did, but he's still your father.
And he's dying.
Yeah.
And he's going to draw his last breath in prison.
Not the VIP suite of Metropolis General.
But only if you're still willing to go through with this.
I don't think I like the sound of this.
Chloe, a dying man has little to lose.
My father used a bizarre blood platelet cocktail to raise the dead,
then pinned the murders of the research team on his son.
Who knows what tactics he'll use to avoid going to prison.
Yeah, but the FBI...
The FBI guaranteed our safety.
I mean, they're putting me and my father in protective custody until after the trial.
Then what?
Lex, are you trying to scare me?
I'm worried about you, Chloe.
I want you to have all the facts before you walk into that courtroom.
Your father's intimidated me long enough.
I'm not backing down.
I'm not going to let you get away with this.
I'm going to have to get you out of prison.
What is this?
A key.
Unfortunately, not the one we're both looking for.
If you want to play games, I'll leave.
Clark.
My lawyers have told me that your name has appeared on the prosecution's witness list.
I can only assume that Lex has you buying into his version of our edifice.
I'm a poor misguided, et cetera, et cetera.
Buy into this.
You're a murderer.
I didn't kill my parents, Clark.
I certainly didn't shed any tears at their funeral.
You have no idea what it's like to grow up under the thumb of an abusive father.
Someone who'd stop at nothing to establish absolute control over you.
Your son does.
Lex is an expert by now.
An expert at lies and subterfuge.
That key you're holding, it opens a door.
Third floor, east wing, Luther Mansion.
You'll be fascinated by what you find.
I'm not walking into some kind of trap.
The last time I listened to you, I became a lab rat at Summerhold.
Clark.
I don't want to harm you.
I want to enlighten you.
You want answers.
You've got to find them.
Answers you won't believe.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Before you jump to conclusions, Clark.
You told me you stopped investigating me.
I did.
You did.
Then what is this?
I understand how you could think all this is about you.
But in fact, it's about me.
More lies.
There's so much in my own life I can't explain.
I've survived countless brushes with death.
And it all started with this car crash.
If I'm guilty of anything,
it's that I've inherited my father's eccentric curiosity for the unexplained.
You've inherited his dishonesty.
Clark, look me in the eye and tell me you don't have any hidden places of your own
where you keep your deep, dark secrets.
Ever since I've met you, I've been defending you.
Making excuses for you to people.
Like Pete.
Like my parents.
Telling them you can trust Lex Luthor.
He's a good guy.
He's nothing like his father.
I was wrong.
Clark!
I can't believe you pretended to be my friend for three years just to investigate me.
Clark.
I'm so sorry.
I know how hard this must be for you.
Maybe Kara's right.
She warned me that all my friends would betray me.
Maybe I don't belong here.
Maybe there's a better place for me.
No.
I've done everything in my power to defy Jarell.
Mom, it's only made things worse.
Clark.
Maybe I should go.
Oh, sweetheart.
You don't have to decide anything, right?
This is the end of the world.
It's been a nice minute.
You know, it's been an incredibly difficult time for you.
With Pete gone and Lana leaving.
Lana.
Hold me.
Even though I know you're leaving.
And show me.
All the reasons you stay.
It's just enough to leave.
Lex.
I just wanted to say, bon voyage.
Shouldn't you be at the courthouse?
My father can wait.
Lana, I couldn't let the last person you saw from Smallville
be the shuttle driver looking for his tip.
Lex, I can't thank you enough for everything that you've done for me.
It's pretty clear.
Your destiny lies far beyond the Smallville city limits.
I'm just trying to help you get there.
I don't know what I did to deserve such a great friend,
but I'm glad that you came into my life.
Maybe I'll bump into you on the Champs-Élysées.
Are you gonna be in Paris?
I haven't been in a couple of years, but now I have reason to go.
Common, please don't go, let me leave you and then we can enjoy the chance of reunion.
it'll give me motivation to love you and you'll find it...
I hope he grows to an age when he can go from worries all come to dreams and goodbye.
i am just like you.
please don't go, let me get you, just one more.
please don't go, I only need one last perspective.
please, don't leave me, it's tooavor to ignore my grief.
one moment more
You've got to hold me
Yeah
Maybe I'll believe
So hold me
Even though I know
you're leaving
Lex
Clark still isn't here
and the judge says that if he doesn't show within the next five minutes
he's setting bail for your dad
You tried calling him?
Yes, I called him at home and on his cell phone
There was no answer
Something big must have happened because he flaked on Lana too
Lex, what's going on?
Nothing
I'm just hoping Clark didn't change his mind
You're his best friend
Why would he do that?
There he is
Just in time to save the day
Clark
Hey
Sir
How do you feel about facing prison now that you've been denied bail?
You know, it's nothing new
to be in prison and to be an innocent man
In the end, I have no doubt
that justice is the only way to get out of prison
I don't know if I can do that in prison or not in prison
Justice will prevail
Are you finding an appeal, sir?
Are you saying...
Clark
Thanks for showing up
It means a lot to me
I didn't come here for you, Lex
I came here because it's the right thing to do
This friendship's over
I'm sorry, I'm sorry
Everything you said has come true
I take no pleasure in your anguish, Kal-El
I know that you have great feelings for these people
And they will miss you when you're gone
Ever since the meteor shower brought them nothing but pain
Come with me, Kal-El
And she will ease your suffering
She?
Your birth mother
Lara
She's missed you so much
How could she?
She died
Her love lives on
And will embrace you all the days of your life
If only you had someone other than her
I've receivedPut a medal in being your son
Operation
Maybe then I'd also pick up in your hire
I got a light
I'd understand
Please cut it off
I haven't been able to beat you
Anyone to get any of you?
None
I'm always tough
The keeper of the Wall of Weird?
It's extremely weird.
I'm sorry.
Mark! Wait!
Her name is not Kara.
Her name is Lindsay.
And she's not from Krypton.
Dad, what are you talking about?
Ignore him, tell Al.
Chloe matched her fingerprints to a young girl
who was arrested for shoplifting
16 years ago.
Your name is Lindsay Harrison.
Your name is Kara.
You were driving with your mother
on the day of the meteor shower.
Your car got a direct hit on Route 8.
That's right here near the caves.
Mark, Lindsay's body was never found.
She was just a little girl.
She was a little girl.
You haven't aged a day.
Because I've been waiting for you.
In there.
No, Lindsay.
Jor-El used you.
He stole away your life.
He stripped you of your humanity.
All so he could lure Clark to him.
You two have to come with me right now.
Go with Kara, Carlisle.
I'm not going anywhere!
I'll never be who you want me to be.
Come with me!
What did you do to her?
She served her purpose.
As has Jonathan Kent.
Ken!
Leave my father alone!
Come forward, or he will die.
Come to me.
Carlisle.
Clark!
I've lived a full life, son!
Jor-El can do whatever he wants to do to me.
And London, you're free!
I'll never be free!
Clark!
No!
No one but the King.
How dare you spoil the world?
How dare you!
США
cı
nh
U
What's going on?
Where are you?
I'm in very sad time.
So how does he found
where I am?
Sort of usual.
You stupid trampleza.
Not helping me.
Wow!
¶¶
Thank you.
Kahlil, my son.
¶¶
Now you shall be reborn.